Contact

+923053049898 (Mobile) muhammadbutt70@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-bin-liaquat-708041194 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Successful Business Owner Full-Stack Development Responsive Web Design

Muhammad Bin Liaquat

Web Developer at Pak It Masters

Rawalpindi

Summary

Solution-driven professional excelling in highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions to

challenges and focused on customer satisfaction. Proven experience developing consumer-focused web

sites using React.js, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Node.js, MongoDB, RESTful API, Bootstrap. Experience building products for web users, meeting highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices, usability and speed. Responding to challenges by designing and developing solutions and building web applications aligned to customer's services. Translating solutions into code and working across many different APIs, third-party integrations and databases.

Experience

Pak It Masters Web Developer February 2019 - Present (1 year 7 months) Islamabad, Punjab

- 1. Designed, implemented and monitored web pages and sites for continuous improvement.
- 2. Optimized Frontend and Database web assets for speed and performance.
- 3. Tested websites and performed troubleshooting prior to deployment.
- 4. Created eye catching and functional digital design concepts across various platforms to strengthen company brand and identity.
- 5. Used various technologies, including Node.js, express & MongoDB to write efficient code and optimize corporate website.
- 6. Determined coding requirements for site creation, including e-commerce capability and specialized scripts.
- 7. Established milestones for projects and prepared all team members to meet aggressive deadlines.
- 8. Developed company website using ReactJS and by converting designs to HTML

code.

- 9. Provided end-user training for website maintenance and updating.
- 10. Created site layout and user interface using HTML5, CSS3 & Javascript practices

Butt Universal Travel & Tours

Managing Director

September 2015 - December 2019 (4 years 4 months)

Education

University of Sargodha

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science · (2018 - 2022)

Udemy.com

The Complete 2020 Web Development Bootcamp, Web Development · (2019 - 2020)

Dar E Arqam College Sargodha Intermediate, Fsc-Pre Engineering · (2015 - 2017)

Dar E Arqam School Sargodha Matric, Computer Science · (2012 - 2015)

The Muslim House School Sargodha Primary · (2008 - 2012)